Einstein said that
قال انشتاين
"I never think about the future — it comes soon enough."
" أنا لا أفكر مطلقا بالمستقبل، لأنه سيأتي قريبا "
And he was right, of course.
وبالطبع، لقد كان محقا
So today, I'm here to ask you to think of
لذلك، أنا اليوم لأطلب منكم التفكير في
how the future is happening now.
كيف يحدث المستقبل الآن
Over the past 200 years, the world has experienced
خلال العشرين سنة الماضية، مرّ العالم بتجربة
two major waves of innovation.
موجتين من الإبداع
First, the Industrial Revolution
أولا، الثورة الصناعية
brought us machines and factories, railways,
جلبت لنا الآلات، والمصانع، والسكك الحديدية
electricity, air travel,
والكهرباء، والسفر عن طريق الجو
and our lives have never been the same.
وتغيرت حياتنا كثيرا
Then the Internet revolution
ثم جاءت ثورة الإنترنت
brought us computing power, data networks,
جلبت لنا القدرة الحاسوبية، وشبكات البيانات
unprecedented access
وصول غير مسبوق
to information and communication,
للمعلومات والإتصالات
and our lives have never been the same.
وتغيرت حياتنا كثيرا
Now we are experiencing
ونحن الآن نشهد
another metamorphic change:
تغير تحولي آخر
the industrial Internet.
في الإنترنت الصناعية
It brings together intelligent machines,
يجمع بين الآلات الذكية
advanced analytics,
والتحليلات المتقدمة
and the creativity of people at work.
وإبداع الناس في العمل
It's the marriage of minds and machines.
فهو تزاوج بين العقول والآلات
And our lives will never be the same.
وتغيرت حياتنا كثيرا
In my current role, I see up close
في دوري الحالي، وأرى عن قرب
how technology is beginning to transform
كيف تكون التكنولوجيا بداية لتحويل
industrial sectors that play a huge role
القطاعات الصناعية التي تلعب دورا كبيرا
in our economy and in our lives:
في اقتصادنا وحياتنا
energy, aviation, transportation, health care.
الطاقة، والطيران، والنقل، والرعاية الصحية.
For an economist, this is highly unusual,
لخبير اقتصادي، هذا أمر غير مألوف للغاية،
and it's extremely exciting,
ومثيرة للغاية،
because this is a transformation
لأن هذا التحول
as powerful as the Industrial Revolution and more,
قوي مثل الثورة الصناعية وأكثر من ذلك،
and before the Industrial Revolution,
وقبل الثورة الصناعية
there was no economic growth to speak of.
لم يكن هناك أي نمو اقتصادي يمكن الحديث عنه
So what is this industrial Internet?
إذا، ما هي الانترنت الصناعية؟
Industrial machines are being equipped
يجري تجهيز الآلات الصناعية
with a growing number of electronic sensors
مع عدد متزايد من أجهزة الاستشعار الإلكترونية
that allow them to see, hear, feel
التي تسمح لهم ان يروا، ويسمعوا ، ويشعروا
a lot more than ever before,
أكثر بكثير من أي وقت مضى،
generating prodigious amounts of data.
توليد كميات هائلة من البيانات.
Increasingly sophisticated analytics
تحليلات متطورة على نحو متزايد
then sift through the data,
ثم من خلال التدقيق في البيانات،
providing insights that allow us
تقديم الأفكار التي تسمح لنا
to operate the machines in entirely new ways,
بتشغيل الآلات بطرق جديدة تماما،
a lot more efficiently.
وبكفاءة أكبر
And not just individual machines,
وليس مجرد آلات فردية
but fleets of locomotives, airplanes,
ولكن أساطيل القاطرات والطائرات
entire systems like power grids, hospitals.
أنظمة كاملة مثل شبكات الكهرباء والمستشفيات.
It is asset optimization and system optimization.
فهي تحسين للأصول وللنظام
Of course, electronic sensors
بطبيعة الحال، وأجهزة الاستشعار الإلكترونية
have been around for some time,
كانت هناك لبعض الوقت
but something has changed:
لكن هناك شيئا ما تغير
a sharp decline in the cost of sensors
انخفاض حاد في تكلفة أجهزة الاستشعار
and, thanks to advances in cloud computing,
وبفضل التقدم في مجال الحوسبة السحابية،
a rapid decrease in the cost of storing
انخفاض سريع في تكلفة التخزين
and processing data.
وفي معالجة البيانات
So we are moving to a world
لذلك نحن نتحرك إلى عالم
where the machines we work with
تكون فيه الآلات التي نعمل فيها
are not just intelligent; they are brilliant.
ليست ذكية فقط، بل متألقة
They are self-aware, they are predictive,
فهي واعية، وتستطيع التنبؤ
reactive and social.
ولها ردة فعل واجتماعية
It's jet engines, locomotives, gas turbines,
إنها المحركات النفاثة والقاطرات، وتوربينات الغاز،
medical devices, communicating seamlessly
الأجهزة الطبية، والتواصل بسلاسة
with each other and with us.
مع بعضها، ومعنا
It's a world where information itself
إنه عالم حيث المعلومات نفسها
becomes intelligent and comes to us
أصبحت ذكية، وتأتي إلينا
automatically when we need it
تلقائيا عندما نكون في حاجة إليها
without having to look for it.
دون الحاجة إلى البحث عنها.
We are beginning to deploy
بدأنا نشر
throughout the industrial system
في جميع أنحاء النظام الصناعي
embedded virtualization,
الافتراضية المدمجة،
multi-core processor technology,
وتقنية المعالجات متعددة النوى،
advanced cloud-based communications,
الاتصالات القائمة على الحوسبة السحابية المتقدمة،
a new software-defined machine infrastructure
وبرنامج معرفي جديد للبنية التحتية للآلات
which allows machine functionality
الذي يسمح لوظائف الآلة
to become virtualized in software,
لتصبح افتراضية في مجال البرمجيات،
decoupling machine software from hardware,
فصل الجهاز من البرمجيات والمعدات،
and allowing us to remotely and automatically
ويسمح لنا عن بعد وتلقائيا
monitor, manage and upgrade industrial assets.
مراقبة وإدارة وتطوير الأصول الصناعية.
Why does any of this matter at all?
لماذا هذا الشيء مهم بالنسبة لنا ؟
Well first of all, it's already allowing us
حسنا أولا، أنها تتيح لنا بالفعل
to shift towards preventive,
إلى التحول نحو الوقائية،
condition-based maintenance,
وصيانة على حسب الحالة
which means fixing machines
وهو ما يعني تصليح الآلات
just before they break,
حتى قبل آن تنكسر
without wasting time
دون إضاعة الوقت
servicing them on a fixed schedule.
تقديم خدمة لهم في جدول زمني محدد
And this, in turn, is pushing us towards
وهذا، بدوره، يدفعنا نحو
zero unplanned downtime,
توقف صفري لعدم التخطيط
which means there will be no more power outages,
وهو ما يعني أنه لن يكن هناك المزيد من انقطاع التيار الكهربائي،
no more flight delays.
ولن يكون هناك المزيد من الرحلات المؤجلة
So let me give you a few examples
لذلك، دعوني أعطيكم بعض الأمثلة
of how these brilliant machines work,
لكيفية عمل هذه الآلات الرائعة،
and some of the examples may seem trivial,
وبعض الأمثلة قد تبدو ساذجة ،
some are clearly more profound,
بعضها تبدو أكثر عمقا،
but all of them are going to have a very powerful impact.
ولكن كل منهم سيكون له له تأثير قوي جدا.
Let's start with aviation.
دعونا نبدأ مع الطيران.
Today, 10 percent of all flights
اليوم، 10 في المئة من جميع الرحلات الجوية
cancellations and delays
تلغى أو تأجل
are due to unscheduled maintenance events.
بسبب إجراء صيانة عير مجدولة
Something goes wrong unexpectedly.
بعض الأشياء تحدث بطريقة خاطئة وغير متوقعة
This results in eight billion dollars in costs
مما يسبب خسارة تقدر ب8 مليار دولار
for the airline industry globally every year,
كل سنة لصناعة الطيران في العالم
not to mention the impact on all of us:
ناهيك عن تأثير ذلك على كل واحد منا
stress, inconvenience,
الإجهاد، الإزعاج،
missed meetings as we sit helplessly
والتغيب عن الاجتماعات كما نجلس بلا حول ولا قوة
in an airport terminal.
في مبنى المغادرة بالمطار
So how can the industrial Internet help here?
فكيف يمكن أن تساعد شبكة الإنترنت الصناعي هنا؟
We've developed a preventive maintenance system
قمنا بتطوير نظام الصيانة الوقائية
which can be installed on any aircraft.
والتي يمكن تركيبها على أي طائرة.
It's self-learning and able to predict issues
وهي قابلة للتعلم الذاتي، وقادرة على التنبؤ بالقضايا
that a human operator would miss.
التي من شأن المشغل البشري أن لا ينتبه لها
The aircraft, while in flight,
الطائرة، أثناء طيرانها
will communicate with technicians on the ground.
سوف تتواصل مع الفنيين على الأرض
By the time it lands, they will already know
في الوقت الذي تهبط فيه، سيكونون علموا بالفعل
if anything needs to be serviced.
إذا كان هناك أي شيء يحتاج إلى إصلاح
Just in the U.S., a system like this can prevent
فقط في الولايات المتحدة، مثل هذا النظام يمكن أن يمنع
over 60,000 delays and cancellations every year,
أكثر من 60،000 من التأخير والإلغاء في كل عام،
helping seven million passengers
يساعد سبعة ملايين راكب
get to their destinations on time.
للوصول إلى وجهاتهم في الوقت المحدد
Or take healthcare.
أو أخذ الرعاية الصحية.
Today, nurses spend an average
اليوم، الممرضات يقضون ما معدله
of 21 minutes per shift
21 دقيقة في كل نوبة
looking for medical equipment.
من أجل البحث عن المعدات الطبية
That seems trivial, but it's less time spent
يبدو وقتا تافها، لكن في هذا الوقت يقلص وقت
caring for patients.
رعاية المرضى
St. Luke's Medical Center in Houston, Texas,
مركز سانت لوك الطبي في هيوستن، تكساس،
which has deployed industrial Internet technology
الذي نشر تكنولوجيا الانترنت الصناعية
to electronically monitor and connect
للمراقبة الإلكترونية والاتصال
patients, staff and medical equipment,
بالمرضى ، والطاقم والمعدات الطبية
has reduced bed turnaround times
قد خفضت أوقات تحول السرير
by nearly one hour.
بقرابة ساعة واحدة
If you need surgery, one hour matters.
اذا كنت بحاجة الى عملية جراحية، تأخذ المسألة ساعة واحدة.
It means more patients can be treated,
وهو ما يعني المزيد من المرضى يمكن علاجهم،
more lives can be saved.
يمكن حفظ المزيد من الأرواح.
Another medical center, in Washington state,
مركز طبي آخر، في ولاية واشنطن،
is piloting an application that allows
يتم تجريب أحد التطبيقات التي تسمح
medical images from city scanners and MRIs
للصور الطبية من الماسحات الضوئية والرنين المغناطيسي
to be analyzed in the cloud,
ليتم تحليلها في السحابة،
developing better analytics
تطوير طرق تحليل افضل
at a lower cost.
بتكلفة أقل
Imagine a patient
تخيل مريض
who has suffered a severe trauma,
تعرض لصدمة شديدة،
and needs the attention of several specialists:
ويحتاج انتباه العديد من المتخصصين
a neurologist, a cardiologist,
طبيب أعصاب، طبيب القلب،
an orthopedic surgeon.
جراح العظام.
If all of them can have instantaneous and simultaneous access
إذا كان كل واحد يستطيع الوصول في وقت واحد وبشكل لحظي
to scans and images as they are taken,
لعمليات الفحص والصور عندما تلتقط،
they will be able to deliver better healthcare faster.
سوف يكونوا قادرين على تقديم رعاية صحية أفضل بشكل أسرع.
So all of this translates into better health outcomes,
لذلك كل هذا يترجم إلى نتائج صحية أفضل،
but it can also deliver substantial economic benefits.
ولكن يمكن أيضا تحقيق فوائد اقتصادية كبيرة.
Just a one-percent reduction in existing inefficiencies
مجرد الحد من واحد في المئة في أوجه القصور القائمة
could yield savings of over 60 billion dollars
يمكن أن تسفر عن توفير أكثر من 60 مليار دولار
to the healthcare industry worldwide,
لقطاع الرعاية الصحية في جميع أنحاء العالم،
and that is just a drop in the sea
وهذا مجرد قطرة في بحر
compared to what we need to do to make healthcare
بالمقارنة مع ما يتعين علينا القيام به لجعل الرعاية الصحية
affordable on a sustainable basis.
متاحة بأسعار معقولة وبشكل مستمر.
Similar advances are happening in energy,
وتقدم مشابه يحدث في مجال الطاقة
including renewable energy.
بما في ذلك الطاقة المتجددة.
Wind farms equipped with new remote monitorings and diagnostics
مزارع الرياح مجهزة بأجهزة جديدة للمراقبة عن بعد والتشخيص
that allow wind turbines to talk to each other
التي تسمح لتوربينات الرياح بالتفاعل مع بعضها البعض
and adjust the pitch of their blades in a coordinated way,
وكذلك ضبط الشفرة الخاصة بالهزة بطريقة متناسقة
depending on how the wind is blowing,
اعتمادا على كيفية هبوب الرياح،
can now produce electricity at a cost
ويمكن الآن إنتاج الكهرباء بتكلفة
of less than five cents per kilowatt/hour.
أقل من خمسة سنتات لكل كيلو واط / ساعة.
Ten years ago, that cost was 30 cents,
قبل عشر سنوات، كانت تكلف 30 سنتا،
six times as much.
ستة أضعاف.
The list goes on, and it will grow fast,
القائمة تطول، وسوف تكبر بسرعة،
because industrial data are now growing exponentially.
لأن البيانات الصناعية تزداد الآن بشكل كبير.
By 2020, they will account for over 50 percent
وبحلول عام 2020، سوف تبلغ نسبتهم أكثر من 50 في المئة
of all digital information.
من البيانات الرقمية
But this is not just about data, so let me switch gears
ولكن هذا لا يقتصر فقط على البيانات، لذلك اسمحوا لي تبديل التروس
and tell you how this is impacting already
واقول لكم كيف يمكن أن هذا يؤثر بالفعل
the jobs we do every day,
على وظائف نقوم بها كل يوم،
because this new wave of innovation
بسبب هذه الموجة الجديدة من الابتكارات
is bringing about new tools and applications
جاءت بأدوات وتطبيقات جديدة
that will allow us to collaborate
التي من شأنها أن تسمح لنا بالتعاون
in a smarter and faster way,
بطريقة أسرع وأكثر ذكاء،
making our jobs not just more efficient
مما يجعل وظيفتنا ليست فقط أكثر كفاءة
but more rewarding.
ولكن أكثر جدوى.
Imagine a field engineer arriving at the wind farm
تخيل وصول مهندس الحقل الى مزرعة الرياح
with a handheld device telling her
مع جهاز محمول باليد ليخبرها
which turbines need servicing.
أي التوربينات التي تحتاج إلى خدمة.
She already has all the spare parts,
لديها فعليا جميع قطع الغيار،
because the problems were diagnosed in advanced.
لأنه تم تشخيص المشاكل في مرحلة متقدمة.
And if she faces an unexpected issue,
وإذا واجهت أي مشكلة غير متوقعة،
the same handheld device will allow her to
نفس جهاز محمول يسمح لها
communicate with colleagues at the service center,
بالتواصل مع الزملاء في مركز الخدمة،
let them see what she sees,
السماح لهم برؤية ما ترى،
transmit data that they can run through diagnostics,
نقل البيانات التي يمكن تشغيلها من خلال التشخيص،
and they can stream videos that will guide her,
ويمكنهم تمرير الفيديوهات التي ستقودها
step by step, through whatever complex procedure
خطوة بخطوة، خلال أي عملية معقدة
is needed to get the machines back up and running.
هناك حاجة للحصول على آلات النسخ الاحتياطي والتشغيل.
And their interaction gets documented
وبالتالي توثق تفاعلاتهم
and stored in a searchable database.
ثم تخزن في قاعدة بيانات قابلة للبحث.
Let's stop and think about this for a minute,
دعونا نتوقف ونفكر في هذا لمدة دقيقة،
because this is a very important point.
لأنها نقطة هامة جدا.
This new wave of innovation is fundamentally
هذه الموجة الجديدة من الابتكار هي في الأساس
changing the way we work.
تغير الطريقة التي نعمل بها.
And I know that many of you will be concerned about the impact that innovation might have on jobs.
وأنا أعلم أن الكثيرين منكم قلقين حول أثر الابتكار على وظائفهم.
Unemployment is already high,
البطالة مرتفعة بالفعل،
and there is always a fear that innovation will destroy jobs.
وهناك دائما خوف أن الابتكار سوف يدمر فرص العمل.
And innovation is disruptive.
وهذا الإبتكار ربما يفسد أكثر
But let me stress two things here.
ولكن اسمحوا لي أن أشدد على أمرين هنا.
First, we've already lived through
أولا، لقد عشنا بالفعل من خلال
mechanization of agriculture, automation of industry,
مكننة الزراعة، أتمتة الصناعة،
and employment has gone up,
ومعدل العمالة قد ارتفع،
because innovation is fundamentally about growth.
لأن الابتكار في الأساس هو محور النمو.
It makes products more affordable.
يجعل المنتجات بأسعار معقولة أكثر .
It creates new demand, new jobs.
أنه يخلق طلب جديد، وظائف جديدة.
Second, there is a concern that in the future,
ثانيا، هناك قلق من أن في المستقبل،
there will only be room for engineers,
لن يكون هناك سوى غرفة للمهندسين،
data scientists, and other highly-specialized workers.
علماء البيانات، وغيرهم من العاملين بدرجة عالية من التخصص.
And believe me, as an economist, I am also scared.
وصدقوني، وكخبير اقتصادي، أنا أيضا خائف.
But think about it:
لكن فكر فيها
Just as a child can easily figure out
كما يفكر الطفل ستكتشف بسهولة
how to operate an iPad,
كيف تشغل أيباد
so a new generation of mobile and intuitive
لذلك الجيل الجديد من خدمات الهاتف النقال
industrial applications will make life easier
والتطبيقات الصناعية البديهية سوف تجعل الحياة أسهل
for workers of all skill levels.
للعاملين بكافة مستوياتهم المهارية
The worker of the future will be more like Iron Man
والعامل في المستقبل سوف يكون أقرب للرجل الحديدي
than the Charlie Chaplin of "Modern Times."
من شارلي شابلن من "العصر الحديث".
And to be sure, new high-skilled jobs will be created:
ومما لا شك فيه، سيتم خلق الوظائف التي تتطلب مهارات عالية جديدة
mechanical digital engineers who understand
مهندسي الميكانيكا الرقمية الذين يفهمون
both the machines and the data;
الآلات والبيانات؛
managers who understand their industry
المدراء الذين يفهمون صناعتهم
and the analytics and can reorganize the business
والتحليلات، التي يمكن أن تعيد تنظيم الأعمال
to take full advantage of the technology.
لتحقيق الاستفادة الكاملة من هذه التكنولوجيا.
But now let's take a step back.
ولكن الآن دعونا نأخذ خطوة إلى الوراء.
Let's look at the big picture.
دعونا ننظر إلى الصورة الكبيرة
There are people who argue that today's innovation
هناك أناس يقولون أن الابتكار اليوم
is all about social media and silly games,
كله في وسائل الاعلام الاجتماعية والألعاب السخيفة،
with nowhere near the transformational power
مع أي مكان بالقرب من القوة التحويلية
of the Industrial Revolution.
الثورة الصناعية.
They say that all the growth-enhancing innovations
يقولون أن جميع الابتكارات التي تعزز النمو
are behind us.
هي وراءنا.
And every time I hear this, I can't help thinking that
وفي كل مرة أسمع هذا، لا أستطيع المساعدة في التفكير في أن
even back in the Stone Age,
حتى في العصر الحجري،
there must have been a group of cavemen
يجب أن يكون هناك مجموعة من رجال الكهوف
sitting around a fire one day
جلسوا حول النار يوما ما
looking very grumpy,
وبوجوه غاضبة
and looking disapprovingly at another group of cavemen
وتبحث باستنكار في مجموعة أخرى من رجال الكهوف
rolling a stone wheel up and down a hill,
تحمل الحجر في عجلات أثناء الصعود والنزول من التل
and saying to each other,
ويقولون لبعضهم
"Yeah, this wheel thing,
"نعم، هذا العجلات،
cool toy, sure, but compared to fire,
لعبة باردة، بالتأكيد، ولكن بالمقارنة مع النار،
it will have no impact.
فإنه لن يكون لها تأثير.
The big discoveries are all behind us."
الاكتشافات الكبيرة كلها وراءنا ".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This technological revolution
هذه الثورة التكنولوجية
is as inspiring and transformational
مثل الملهم والتحويلي
as anything we have ever seen.
مثل أي شيء لم نشاهده على الإطلاق
Human creativity and innovation have always propelled us forward.
الإبداع البشري والابتكار دفعت بنا إلى الأمام دائما.
They've created jobs.
فقد خلقت فرص عمل
They've raised living standards.
ورفعت مستويات المعيشة
They've made our lives
لقد جعلوا حياتنا
healthier and more rewarding.
صحية وأكثر جدوى.
And the new wave of innovation
والموجة الجديدة من الابتكار
which is beginning to sweep through industry
التي بدأت تجتاح الصناعة
is no different.
لا تختلف.
In the U.S. alone, the industrial Internet
في الولايات المتحدة وحدها، الإنترنت الصناعية
could raise average income by 25 to 40 percent
يمكنها رفع متوسط ​​الدخل بنسبة 25 الى 40 في المئة
over the next 15 years,
على مدى السنوات ال 15 المقبلة،
boosting growth to rates we haven't seen in a long time,
تعزيز النمو إلى معدلات لم نراها من وقت طويل،
and adding between 10 and 15 trillion dollars to global GDP.
وإضافة ما بين 10 و 15 تريليون دولار من الناتج المحلي الإجمالي العالمي.
That is the size of the entire U.S. economy today.
هذا هو حجم اقتصاد الولايات المتحدة بأكملها اليوم.
But this is not a foregone conclusion.
ولكن هذا ليس امرا مفروغا منه.
We are just at the beginning of this transformation,
نحن فقط في بداية هذا التحول،
and there will be barriers to break,
وسوف يكون هناك حواجز للكسر،
obstacles to overcome.
وعقبات يتعين التغلب عليها.
We will need to invest in the new technologies.
سنحتاج إلى الاستثمار في التكنولوجيات الجديدة.
We will need to adapt organizations and managerial practices.
سوف نحتاج للتكيف مع المنظمات والممارسات الإدارية.
We will need a robust cybersecurity approach
سوف نحتاج إلى تطبيق نهج الأمن السيبراني
that protects sensitive information and intellectual property
الذي يحمي المعلومات الحساسة والملكية الفكرية
and safeguards critical infrastructure from cyberattacks.
والضمانات البنية التحتية الحيوية من الهجمات الإلكترونية.
And the education system will need to evolve
ونظام التعليم سوف يحتاج إلى تطوير
to ensure students are equipped with the right skills.
لضمان تجهيز الطلاب بالمهارات المناسبة.
It's not going to be easy,
انها لن تكون سهلة،
but it is going to be worth it.
لكنها تستحق كل هذا العناء.
The economic challenges facing us are hard,
التحديات الاقتصادية التي تواجهنا صعبة،
but when I walk the factory floor,
ولكن عندما أمشي على أرض المصنع،
and I see how humans and brilliant machines
وأرى كيف البشر والآلات الرائعة
are becoming interconnected,
تصبح مترابطة،
and I see the difference this makes
وأرى أن هذا يجعل الفرق
in a hospital, in an airport,
في المستشفى، في المطار،
in a power generation plant, I'm not just optimistic,
في محطة توليد الطاقة، وأنا لست متفائلا فقط،
I'm enthusiastic.
أنا متحمس.
This new technological revolution is upon us.
هذه الثورة التكنولوجية الجديدة علينا.
So think about the future — it will be here soon enough.
لذلك فكروا في المستقبل - سيكون قريبا بما فيه الكفاية.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)